LYNN **RICHARDS**

leenrichards@yahoo.com

C 778.987.0378 0

Vancouver BC, Canada

linkedin.com/in/lynnrichards1



github.com/leenrichards

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Web developer with extensive experience in designing, developing, testing, and deploying applications. Demonstrated ability in leading software development projects, performing database management, and customer support. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry

Vancouver, BC

Full Stack Developer Certification

Cornell University

Ithaca, NY

Master of Engineering: Computer Science

The American University

Washington, D.C.

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- MS SQL Server, MongoDB
- CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Node, REACT, Bootstrap
- MS Office, Adobe Suite
- Git, Trello, Teamwork, Zendesk, and more...

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Fluent in English, French and Arabic.
- US Citizen with Canadian Permanent Residency.
- Avid cyclist, with top podium finishes at various races in B.C and AZ.

WORK HISTORY

IT Consultant - NGN Productions

Vancouver, BC • 09/2017-09/2021

- Used Google Apps Script (GAS) to automate a film repository which allowed producers to update and filter worldwide movie releases and generate automatic weekly reports for company executives.
- Managed customer support, website maintenance and management of the cast & crew database.

Project manager - Cycling Components Network

Vancouver, BC • 11/2015 - 05/2017

- Led of all phases of the software development lifecycle for cutting-edge online registration systems with clients such as USA Cycling and Triathlon Canada.
- Maintained project schedules, work breakdown structures, issue logs, and status reports leading a team of 8 software developers and ensured timely completion of deliverables.
- Gathered, analyzed, and presented statistical membership reports for Triathlon Canada and The Vancouver Sun Run by writing an application that generated and compiled historical membership data.

Web Developer - Self

Phoenix, AZ • 09/2009 - 11/2015

• Maintained client/server solutions for *The Cawley Company*, a worldwide provider for badge identification systems. Applications included an encrypted database-driven badge ordering system for all Carlson Hotel branches, and online employee badge ordering systems for Cintas, Avis and Budget offices nationwide.

Corporate Quality Senior Software Engineer - Intel Corporation

Chandler, AZ • 10/1995 - 09/2006

- Responsible for the design and development of the central repository for Intel's Customer Operational Shared Resource (COSR).
- Contributed to each step of COSR's n-tier application development lifecycle: design, development, deployment & support.
- Product owner of Intel's Change Management Information System: a clientserver application that automates the notification of product changes to Intel's customer base worldwide. Contributed to the design, development, testing & support of the application.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST